welcome to launched I'm Charlie Chapman
and today I'm excited to bring you the
prolific iOS development YouTuber Shan
[Music]
[Applause]
Allen Sean welcome to the show it's
great to be here great to be here I uh I
miss the background music though the
nice yeah yeah well now you made it
weird cuz I was going to add that in
post uh so it sounded like it maybe give
it a little Reverb but uh good we just
get it awkward right off the bat and get
that out of the way do it yeah yeah all
right so I'm super excited about this I
haven't just a little background here uh
we've met a couple times since getting
here never met before and I've been like
awkwardly avoiding asking you questions
uh I'll start talking about stuff he's
like I gotta leave I yeah yeah literally
just like walking away um so I finally
get to get into things and something I
haven't told you yet is uh when I when I
joined the like iOS Community it was
kind of a weird thing I'd been doing
like web development for a long time and
I got an opportunity to do join an iOS
team so I was like yes I'm going to jump
on that and then I went home and
downloaded xcode for the very first time
I literally knew didn't know what
anything about Swift anything and the
first thing I watched was a Shan Allen
video the very first thing the literally
actually no I'm lying uh the first thing
is I started like I read a couple
chapters or a couple sentences of
Apple's like Swift book and then I was
like all right I'm going to YouTube
right to YouTube yeah exactly do you
remember which video it was it yes it
was the storyboards versus code video
and I think that's like it's a perfect
example of what I like about your video
style which we'll get into here in a
little bit but it was like I didn't know
what storyboards were had never heard
that word before and you like helped
give me the context for a thing so that
whenever I was at a meeting at work or
something I had some of that context as
a like complete new Junior person it was
so cool yeah yeah know that's awesome I
remember the whole storyboards
programmatic debates funny looking back
on it I was looking for the title and I
was like wow I guess I have been doing
this long enough to say that I remember
the olden days CU nobody talks about
that really anymore I just had a
conversation with Jesse a little last
night at the speaker dinner when I guess
she mentioned she hasn't really touched
UI kit and at first I was like wow how
is that possible but then you're like oh
yeah s eyes really been out for like 5
years now so it's not know someone can
still have a good amount of experience
and have never touched you like it yeah
so before we get into YouTube and your
like Indie app thing that you've got
going uh I want to give everyone a
background on who you are so the three
questions I always ask is uh where are
you from um do you have a formal
education related to what you do and
then we can talk about your career that
like led up to starting your YouTube
channel all right let's do it so I'm
from uh Pennsylvania small town and and
the formal education no I don't have a
computer science degree which actually
plays in the whole start of the YouTube
channel and everything I have a finance
and economics degree so the whole reason
I even like we out to San Francisco in
the first place was to get into like
venture capital and all that stuff um
but then I learned how to code and that
completely changed changed my whole life
um so yeah the career leading up to
becoming a developer was working at a
small startup I was the growth lead so
I'm trying to build these static web
pages for my Google ads campaigns um or
no I'm sorry had I needed static web
pages and then I didn't want to bother
my developers cuz it's like a team of
three and they're building the product
so hey can I have my little landing page
so I just learned myself and then that
magical moment of I have this idea in my
head of what I want to be on the screen
you type a couple words and then it
shows up on the screen and it was just
mind-blowing and I was like oh this is
what I want to do like I caught the bug
right away oh yeah it's like an
addicting like I don't know if you all
have many probably have experienced it
themselves but if you've ever witnessed
somebody else do it like coding is hard
like we all like to say like oh what we
do is really easy but when you're first
trying to understand these Concepts it's
really hard but that moment where like
you get something to work and you like
your brain lights up and then the extra
bit is when it you want to change a
small thing and then you like go back in
and you fight that you get that to work
and it's just this feedback loop of uh
like whatever the drug is in your brain
that makes you happy it was just a real
Revelation for me because I I didn't
start coding till my mid-30s so I just
grew up thinking like like you said oh
that's magic that's way too hard I could
never do that no way and then when I
like did it as simple as it was just
basic HTML CSS nothing insane but that
little moment was like oh this is
like we're good I can do this like let's
go and then I was just that's all I did
I just became obsessed with it for a
little bit so at this point it's web
development then right or literally just
static HTML Pages yes but I knew that's
not what I wanted to do so at the same
startup they were building a
crossplatform app this is in 2014 by the
way um and they built it in ionic which
is Javascript I think know what it's
called ionic oh ionic I didn't know what
it was I just knew the app sucked and I
was I was a big apple Fanboy and I was
playing with it and I was like I can't
believe like I'm a part of this team
building this app like I was like oh my
God I'm like embarrassed of it I didn't
want to show anybody too so anyway
that's when I knew I was like it was
going to be native iOS development and
it was always iOS just cuz apple apple
Fanboy okay so you went straight from
like I need to build a static HTML site
to I want to do some kind of native iOS
stuff what was the next steps like how
do you start doing it yeah so at the
time again I'm in San Francisco and boot
camps you know were pretty big back then
and there was an iOS boot camp called
mobile makers that like went out of
business I think in 2016 2017 um so I
was like one of the last cohorts to go
through that um pretty successful cohort
though because there's only eight of us
I think that's probably why they went
out of business but I think two of them
ended up at Apple eventually one of them
was like a founding iOS Dev on like the
coinbase app so they well
yeah anything did came like three or
four years later but they like at the
gate they got they got hired pretty
quickly wow so how was I mean how was
that experience i' I've never gone
through a boot camp or known somebody
personally who's gone through those it
was interesting especially with what I
do now in like teaching cuz like they
teach you the The Bare Bones like they
teach you the basics right um but yeah
it was just8 hours a day that that's
what I say was good about it because we
can all say like oh I'm going to learn
to code I'm going to be self-disciplined
I'm going to do 5 hours a day whatever
life happens you know people don't do
that it's like when people say I'm going
to get up and go to the gym every
morning
like okay I'm going to learn a language
and then you're like you're just keeping
up your street with one du lingo thing
exactly so the benefit of the boot camp
is you know you paid I think I paid 11
Grand so like yeah I'm going to be there
every day 8 to five right so it forced
me to like really focus on it for a
short period of time yeah that's cool so
okay you get through that boot camp what
next where you just like I'm getting an
iOS job that's what I'm want yeah that
was the goal I I applied to like 60
companies which and at the time I
thought that was a large number but then
like hearing from a lot of people I was
like oh I got lucky um wow but it only
resulted in three interviews and I
failed all three of them except one of
them I thought went well in I'm sorry no
I knew it went bad but I knew I was
better than that so I told them I was
like hey do you have anything I can do
over the weekend like give me a
take-home project is there anything I
can show you my skills because I feel
like that interview did not represent
like my skill set yeah so like okay cool
here do this you know little take on
Project knocked it out in the weekend I
guess I like blew away their
expectations and then they sent me an
email Monday like wow this was very
impressive to do over weekend uh why
don't you come in I misread the email
why don't you come in to meet the team
my naive was like I got the job they're
going to hire me I missed I missed the
part which is basically like the final
interview which you've all done final
interviews that's the 5H hour you're
talking to five different people you're
on the Whiteboard so I'm I walked into
that thing thinking I'm just like a
little meet and greet Hi I'm the new
member of the team and so I did no prep
no nothing uh luckily it went well
enough that they hired me it probably
helped with the nerves a little bit oh
yeah until the moment you find out like
what you did you're like yeah that's
true that's true luckily like obviously
the Whiteboard went horrible but the
culture interviews with like the CTO and
the CEO went very well so I think that's
kind of what did it in the end yeah it's
weird interviewing like I know on either
side interviewing is a hard thing
finding somebody on that side is also
really hard but the live coding
interviews especially like over Zoom it
just feel it feels like you're
interviewing somebody on their like code
presentation skills not really how good
they are at like creating code alone and
then submitting a PR or something which
is 90% of what we all actually do M yeah
yeah that's interesting okay so then you
got the job what was what was that
experience like like what were you
building and yeah so it was it was a
company called Breathometer they were
actually the first um they were on Shark
Tank they were the first to get all five
sharks invested I think they got like a
million dollars this is like
2013 and it was like a at the time it
was like an alcoholic like obviously
thing right do a breathalizer Breyer
test thing right so was it aice that you
like yeah it hooked into the it hooked
into the headphone jack rip um so it
would been gone anyway but what they
sold me on like that wasn't why I went
there they were going to do this um like
this breath thing that could detect uh
acetone in your breath which for for
like you know diabetics or like losing
weight anyway was a cool like Fitness
type angle and they brought me on to
basically build that app and that was
kind of like their next phase that's
what they sold me on I'm telling you
this because a lot of times startups
will like paint this beautiful picture I
like oh you're going to do this we raise
our series a we'll give you a raise you
know so just be careful of that because
I got burned by basically I got sold on
the one project got put on a different
project which is like a oral health
thing that I couldn't care less about
and then like three weeks after I
started our man oh by the way I got I
signed on for 60 Grand which obviously
that is different everywhere in the
country uh for a developer in San
Francisco that is below minimum wage i'
would say so the my vice president came
up and said okay hey you're you're doing
very well we're underpaying you because
what they did they hired two of us at
the same time and they both gave us that
so they were trying to get like a two
for one deal two two Junior developers
don't know anything for the price of one
kind of um so anyway he knew he was like
okay we need to not not anything crazy
but just market rate yeah yeah um but
again it was the whole series a promise
hey we're going to raise our series a
next month when that happens we'll bump
you up ah yeah ah the series they got
delayed uh you know so here we are that
was in like February and then we're you
know four or five months later still
getting the runaround and then finally I
was like I'd got some contracts on the
side and I had enough to like go
full-time so I was like hey I I didn't
like Bluff or anything I was like I'm
putting in my two weeks you know like
I'm out and they like panicked they're
like whoa whoa whoaa what do you want
what do you want what do you want so I
said 120 and then they came back with
100 and I was like okay um and you
stayed on uh for a little bit longer
then the as some startups do the company
started like falling apart yeah that's
another thing about startups I'm sure
most of you have like some um experience
in it but especially like Silicon Valley
and everything you think everyone has
their together from the outside everyone
knows what they're doing they're a bunch
of geniuses and it's just a complete
circus behind the scenes like re cat
right reat like re yeah I mean saying
it's a circus behind the scenes it's a
circus in front of the scenes as well as
most people here have probably seen uh
yeah we literally have a little spinning
wheel and plushies um wow yeah it's very
circus-like isn't it um yeah but yeah
yeah
like any company you go to they're
trying to sell you but like startups by
the nature of having raised rounds uh
one of their skill sets is pitching
people so yeah yeah you can get pitched
pretty hard especially if it's like your
first experience with these typ of
companies and stuff so then the next
step is continuing on with me being just
naive dumb Sean doesn't know anything
about the industry right so I got burned
by that and then I was like a year and a
half into my career again self-taught
just did a boot camp learned on the
internet internet I got a recruiter
email from Facebook which they recruit
everybody you know I think once you're
like on LinkedIn for over a year with
like a developer job you just get like a
automatic email from these compan Bots
that are scraping yeah but again I
didn't know any better I'm like oh
Facebook wants me okay like great yeah
so I kind of got not not a big head but
I was like oh I'm going to go for that
so I like and I knew this job was coming
to an end so I like quit that job and I
was like I'm going to spend the next you
know month or two just practicing
cracking the coding interview whiteboard
stuff just basically interview prep um
to long story short I went and
interviewed at a couple of the big
companies and just got like laughed out
of the room basically like again the
Whiteboard because I don't have a
computer science degree so all the types
of questions you're going to get asked
at a Facebook interview I just did did
horribly on like I don't think I got
asked iOS questions really like one time
I interviewed at you actually at YouTube
even after I had the YouTube channel and
they knew I was for iOS and I didn't get
asked a single iOS question that's so
yeah that's so interesting in the job
description is IOS yeah yeah yeah I
don't yeah that's really strange but
this is actually where the the Genesis
of the YouTube channel comes in because
I started my YouTube channel cuz I was
pissed off and it was like out of spite
cuz I felt I went through that
experience YouTube YouTube decided not
to hire me I'm going to get them to pay
no I'm sorry this YouTube was a few
months later this was after the Facebook
one um just cuz I felt like like robbed
I was like I know I'm a pretty decent
iOS developer and I just felt like that
wasn't a good representation of like
what I could do that type of interview
so I was like okay I'm just going to put
all my knowledge out on the internet and
and someday you know after 2 3 four
years whatever someone will just know me
and they'll want me and they'll hire me
right cuz I it was like a recruiting
networking thing it was more than like
I'm I'm not making a business out of
this I'm using this to try and get a job
no the business didn't come till like I
was 3 years into it um oh that's
interesting that's the that's the origin
of this podcast too like I I was in
Consulting like I described earlier
and I knew I was going to get sucked
back into like the Microsoft tech stack
cuz that's why they hired me which would
be fair and so I was like I need a job
that says iOS but I knew nobody would
hire me if I had 6 months of experience
so I was like What if I can trick people
to talk to me for an hour on the
internet kind of work yeah and it worked
right like yeah it was really helpful
for networking so so yeah so essentially
it was going to be like a whoops um just
like an online resume you know yeah
exactly basically and like building a
brand and all that stuff just to people
just building your brand sounds cheesy
but just I wanted people to know me and
know my skill set know what I could do
just show them um so I'm a big believer
in like like show me what you can do
don't tell me you know bull um but yeah
so that's how it got started and then it
evolved into like oh I'm actually like
helping people a and like just going to
the very beginning what was the
beginning like what were you doing were
you just uh teaching Frameworks were you
like I know all of your current stuff
but I intentionally avoided going back
as much as I wanted no I mean I so I at
the time I was watching a lot of uh
Casey niat videos this is anybody that
watches YouTube a lot this is when Casey
was doing his daily Vlogs back back in
the prime um so I started doing some
Vlogs about like my life in San
Francisco as like a developer
skateboarding and like I did have a
booster Bo oh really oh you a booster
board wow you really did do the cas I
did not actually film on it cuz I was
terrified of it yeah that would be scary
yeah I wasn't that good at it um talking
about uh well I almost said Swift UI
talking about story boards on boosted
so so I did like kind of Vlogs because I
knew that is what kind of made me unique
like actually being in San Francisco and
Silicon Valley and like kind of showing
that cuz again in 2017 there wasn't a
ton of people doing that like now you
kind of get that all the time but um
yeah so I did that and then also just
kind of I always knew to kind of teach
below what I knew if that makes sense
yeah I I've always tried to not like act
like I know more than I do so like even
now like my my content's pretty much for
like Junior developers pretty basic for
the most part um and that's also because
I don't want the miscon misperception of
like acting like I owe no more than I do
yeah and like I know I don't want to
feel like a fraud you're you're there's
already enough imposter syndrome that
when you're like trying to teach
something above your skill level you
know so yeah did you find like once you
started doing that did you start feeling
more confident because like the idea of
teaching somebody is like oh I I guess I
do kind of know what I'm talking about
yeah I mean when you teach something you
definitely have to like know it way
better than just hey I read the
documentation once I built it and work
it's working yeah there you go yeah no
you definitely have to and in the
beginning you know this just the
learning curve you know the YouTube
comments can be a little brutal and a
lot like really never heard that well
well nowadays yeah but they're right
most of the time they like oh you messed
this up why you why you even teaching
this topic you don't know what you're
talking about CU you messed up this you
know little aspect of it um you know got
that a few times in the earlier in the
career and that was kind of like a
wakeup call to be like oh I need to
research these videos more and like kind
of like cover every angle like kind of
like know everything about the API kind
of before I start teaching it so in in
the early days I feel like there was an
ERA where YouTubers talking about about
how you should approach comments was a
Hot Topic I haven't heard that in a
while though but you were doing it
during that era so it sounds like you're
on the you should look at comments and
like use them as feedback yeah I mean
it's I don't think anything has changed
I think I learned and adapted because I
I even do it in my courses now sometimes
people say like you repeat yourself a
lot because I'll like I know you might
be thinking about this because it's like
I can like hear the YouTube comments as
I'm like explaining something you know
after after years of doing it so I
always try to like you know head it off
at the past
Eight Mile it I like address it before
they like tell me Tell to me so oh
that's interesting okay so you started
doing that uh where's the point where I
mean I guess really the question is did
it get an audience really quickly or
were you kind of just making this thing
and you were doing it as a fun hobby
there was only a couple people watching
it mean yeah that's how they all start
um it took me 6 months to get my first
500 subscribers okay and then I did a
series um my first interview prep series
things on like you know deleg protocols
or classes versus struck just like the
very basic cuz that's what I was doing
at the time I was doing interviews so I
was like I'm interviewing at all these
places here's what I'm getting asked
non-stop so I took like the top
questions I was getting asked and made a
video about each one oh that's really
and I would say that's kind of what made
my channel you know take off cuz I went
from so 6 months to get to 500
subscribers and then another 6 months to
get from about 10,000 from 500 to about
10,000 yeah that's like hockey stick
yeah that was that was like a playlist
of I don't know 10 to 15 videos I don't
know and that that's kind of what got
things going what do you think like was
the main obviously the content has to be
good but in terms of like finding that
first group that causes the snowball was
that was it like a SEO kind of thing
like were you hitting the right
questions do you play that game like
how's that yeah you have to I mean cuz
you know we all go on to YouTube to
search for things I imagine right so you
kind of put yourself in those shoes on
what do I think are most topics being
searched and I knew the interview
questions uh once were but I think what
differentiates me a little bit and like
I'm not saying I'm for everybody right
everybody learns differently so there's
a you know certain teacher for each like
learning style but I think what
differentiates me is I learned how like
the people watching my content are like
I'm going to go on YouTube and learn to
code and like that's like exactly how I
learned so you know I I wasn't I wasn't
like a child prodigy don't have a
computer science degree again I didn't
start coding till I was like 32 so I
remember what it was like to not know
anything be like scared and try to learn
how to code from YouTube videos so I
always keep that in mind when I'm like
teaching things and explaining things
so I think that's kind of what
differentiated you know my content what
made people resonate with me especially
people in in those same shoes that were
doing that same thing right and you you
mentioned earlier like you're still kind
of aiming at that Junior midlevel uh
developer so does that mean like has the
target audience grown with you or do you
like you mentioned repeating yourself do
you feel like you're still reaching kind
of the same audience it's a new kind of
cohort of viewers or something that
you're kind of targeting yeah it's
interesting cuz there are some people
that have been around for like a very
long time I see Dan and Michaela sitting
in the front row Dan's been around for
like day one we're doing live streams to
like 10 people wow there um so yeah
definitely people have stuck around um
there is there is definitely new cohorts
uh all the time but it's been fun like
watching people evolve cuz now that I've
been doing it for seven years I've seen
people go from like the just learning
phase to now that are all these like big
tech companies like 5 years into the
career they're killing it now it's like
oh I remember you when you were you know
what is that so what you're describing
sounds like a little Community is that
in YouTube comments or is there
somewhere else where you're kind of
engaging with the audience uh mainly
Twitter Twitter oh yeah yeah yeah
there's some people that are uh YouTube
comments a lot but it's mostly like
Twitter yeah that's the yeah Twitter
seems like or well the micro blogging
platform of choice whatever it is
tomorrow um but it seems like that's I
think guber is says it all the time
where it's like that's the best comment
system that he can imagine for a Blog it
feels like it's better designed for that
than the comments under a YouTube video
or something Reddit also it for like a
different type of audience it feels like
could also be that right yeah no I just
I like the back and forth on Twitter at
least on my back end on YouTube like the
comments it's very easy to get lost um
because there's no like mention system
like when people tag me on Twitter it
shows up at the top of my notification
feed I sees it I see it I sees it um I
sees it sees it um yeah but YouTube kind
of they kind of get lost after a while
so usually I'll reply once to YouTube
comment and like that's it it's gone
into The Ether there's no like back and
forth yeah yeah it's not a place for a
conversation or for other people early
to jump in even though it technically
can it doesn't feel natural the same way
yeah and they keep tweaking the homepage
to move things around and that's
confusing yeah yeah that's true so okay
so at this point you're getting the
hockey stick growth uh you got your
silver button or whatever what is it no
no not yet that's 100,000 I think I got
that in October of 20122 oh wow okay
later okay okay so going back to that
though at this point where you like hm
this could be like a business business
like were you making money already
through YouTube I mean you make a little
bit on AdSense but it would be like a
hundred bucks a month and maybe I would
get like a small sponsor here or there
for 100 back then like 100 or 200 so it
was nothing that I thought I could make
into a business at that point right it
took three like three years of growing
an audience until I actually was like oh
I think this could be like a business um
and ALS when you say three year that's 3
years of you like this is a tool for
networking and finding a job that was
completely how you were thinking about
that cor correct y well I just I didn't
know what would happen like I knew just
becoming known in the community you know
for whatever reason like I knew like
that would open doors what doors I I
don't know right give me no but like I
just knew that it would be a nice asset
um cuz it it's like you know your
network is your net worth and it's just
another way of building a network so I
didn't know what would happen from it
but I knew it'd be good to have yeah and
it feels like a rare thing so you
probably want to hold on to like oh I
have this I need to not let it go and I
mean it is unique I mean there's well
now there's more people doing it but at
the time when I started there was like
four other iOS Dev YouTubers so it was
kind of like a unique thing yeah that's
cool so okay so you said about 3 years
in it started feeling like it could be a
business did you change gears did you
change how you're doing things or what
was that like um it was so let me go
back a little bit because it wasn't
until I launched my first course uh that
I was like oh this could be a business
because I knew it would make a decent
amount of money but it like blew away
expectations and I think obviously like
Co had something to do with it cuz I
launched it at the end of 2019 and you
know my business did very well during Co
I feel very like bad saying that um but
because you know everyone's stuck IND
doors everyone's like I want to learn a
new skill let me try something I work at
an e-commerce site so it was similar
yeah yeah so that's when it was like oh
okay this is it we can do this yeah okay
so oh yeah so then once you decided to
do that what was the game plan were you
making content based on sponsorship
deals where you're going out and looking
for sponsors like how do you kind of
build this into a sustainable no I I
didn't start going out looking for
sponsors until actually just recently um
when I just started to kind of like make
a push cuz the bad thing and maybe some
indie devs can can know this I was um
talking to Yi about this last night that
once you uh make a certain amount of
money especially like an India app where
it's kind of on autopilot same thing
once I have a couple courses out there
like you can really struggle with
motivation um cuz you know you can coast
and still be fine right it takes a long
time until it starts falling apart and
then catching back up is like
way harder at that point so that's where
I'm at right now you know I just people
may know I just kind of launched a new
course because my old courses they kind
of die after 3 to four years you know if
you build something on iOS 13 and iOS 14
especially in Swift UI it's just a pain
to go back and update you have to
basically re-record everything because
it Chang content that you can just go up
exactly yeah so the reason I was saying
that is you were asking um I can't
remember I went like how how did you
change kind of how you were doing the
the YouTube channel to make a bus so the
big shift was going after views versus
going after the right views so meaning I
can do a video I my channel could be so
much bigger if I wanted it to be because
you can just make General software
developer stuff like I have some videos
that do very well like 37 tips for
junior software developers and that gets
a ton of views but that's JavaScript
developers watch that you know they're
they're not buying my courses yeah so
now that was the shift and trying to get
more views more subscribers which is
just a vanity metric doesn't really do
anything for you I switched it to okay
I'm gonna do this super Niche iOS thing
that is going to drive traffic to my
courses or make people think like oh I
like the way he teaches and then explore
more like on the courses so I kind of
focus more on like like for example
100,000 view video about General
software development does almost nothing
for me or my business but because the
way you're making money is through the
courses that you're selling so a a
YouTube video that gets 1500 views which
from the outside looks like a failure oh
that video sucked but that's that's 1500
people that are learning from me that
could you know Drive traffic to the to
the website so it's kind of it again to
sum it up the shift was going after the
right viewer instead of any viewer yeah
I mean I guess that's like a marketing
101 kind of thing is like you can buy a
Super Bowl ad but there's going to be a
million people that don't care about
your product that see it or way more
than a million people exactly uh or you
could buy a ad in a like magazine that
it doesn't get very many people but the
people every like 100% of the people are
going to care about your product there
yeah yeah that's interesting so that's
why you're not like dropping phones on
day one to see if they Smash and stuff
yeah interesting okay so at this point
are you still doing Contracting work to
mix with it or like what's the what's
the sort of makeup of the business while
you're building this out yeah so it it
was just purely videos and courses in
the summer of 2020 I did a pretty big
project because uh he was taking my
course and I told him though like five
times he's like I want you to build this
app for me I want you to build this app
for me I was like no no no so then
finally I got around to like okay I'll
do it but like here are my terms I think
it was like 100 Grand U half paid up
front I you know I just started listing
things like if I'm going to do this like
it's going it's I'm going to make it so
like I'd be stupid to say no kind of
thing um so yeah I worked with uh Tim
Condon there is over there he worked
with me on that project because we did
uh um did in Swift did it Swift on the
server he handled that oh wow so anyway
in 2020 that was a pretty big project uh
for me like income wise and then um but
that was kind of like the last one I did
after that I was like no I just I wanted
to focus on building my business cuz I
mean it's a classic saying like if I'm
giving someone else my time I'm building
their business sure I may be paid well
in the short term but like especially
with the thing like YouTube and the
videos like it just compounds right I
always compare it to like just building
another brick on the wall um every time
I release a video because those videos
are out there you know a video I did
three years ago still getting good views
still driving people to the website so
okay so you you're focusing on the sort
of video and training and all of that
but you're not at this point really
day-to-day building software like for a
company or for yourself or anything what
how are you keeping up with it how are
you making sure everything you're saying
is still relevant like what's the method
for keeping up with that yeah just watch
a lot of wwc videos a lot of um
documentation that kind of stuff and
yeah cuz I did a lot of like the new
stuff that came out too so there's
there's not a lot of like no one really
knows yet you know right aside from the
WC videos and and I guess like again
going with the like the target audience
it is more introductory level thing so
Mak sense well and also the way I
thought about that is just it's like a
pyramid right there's way more people
looking for the introductory stuff like
the more advanced the niche you go the
smaller the audience gets right so it's
like yeah you can Target those Niche
things but it's hard to build a business
out of yeah you'd have to start charging
way more which that probably at certain
niches maybe they have more disposal
income because they're more senior but
yeah it's probably a lot more
challenging I also think and maybe I
don't know people can say but I don't
think senior developers like to buy
video courses I think they want to like
get me right to the answer give me the
documentation I don't want to watch yeah
I don't want to watch a 15-minute video
I don't need that just like point so
that's also why I keep it basic because
I don't think see typically right in
general yeah yeah that makes sense now
what seems like it would be really
helpful this is a segue for the for the
professionals here what seems like it
would be really helpful is if uh you had
an app of your own that helped feed into
the content that you were making and
made that classic Disney flywheel did
you ever think about making an app I did
I did I did well you kind of let into it
a little bit ago about like how do you
keep up with things cuz what I started
to feel like started to feel like a
mathematician that just taught like
fifth grade math all day oh wow you know
what I mean and it's like well how how
I'm not really flexing my muscles like
I'm kind of feel stagnant um you know I
see everyone else building cool stuff so
I kind of made the decision to try my
own Indie app made a huge mistake though
uh cuz I learned distribution is the
hardest thing which is pretty common
knowledge right but me I'm pretty naive
if you can't tell I was like I can I can
I'm good I'll I'll figure it out I'll
I'll figure out distribution you know I
have an audience I have like well yeah
well but yeah but I made it app for
YouTube creators if I would have made an
app for if I would have made an app for
like a general audience or iOS
developers yeah so I guess that's that
was the point I was trying to make that
was the lesson learned I thought
distribution was going to be easier than
it was it was not in hindsight I would
have been like okay I need to build
build an app for developers or a general
app like I'm spoilers uh the job I'm at
is podcast app you know everyone in the
audience use a podcast or a habit
Tracker app or a dark Noise app I don't
know if you heard of that one you know
anyone it took him a second I caught him
off guard um but you know what I mean
like a more General app for like the
audience so um yeah I did start my own
app but the mistake was doing it you
know not in my Niche but it also
scratched my own itch I use it every day
I built it for myself
so what is the app what was the decision
point for going into it and like how did
you launch it why did you run into
distribution problem yeah so so the
app's called Creator view it's
essentially an app for people making
money on YouTube like like myself
running a business to track everything
schedule content track your income track
your taxes it's basically like a
business manager tool which is a pretty
Niche concept is it hitting like YouTube
apis or like what's how is that a little
bit cuz I do I do some basic like
analytics but for the most part it's
just all I have a little calendar that's
all my own stuff it's not not pulling
down from YouTube or anything like that
um and essentially where that came from
is I had a Notes app that had all my
business stuff in it or or in the notes
app and I had a Google giant Google
spreadsheet and I remember like trying
to strategize about my business I would
have my spreadsheet up I would have all
kinds of notes and i' be like there's
got to be like a I wish I had like an
iPad app cuz I remember i' be like
walking around like looking so that was
the original idea was like I need an
iPad app that can like do all this and I
wanted it to be like nice Apple you know
typical stuff so yeah that's what kind
of started it and like as you were
building it you were kind of feeding
that back into the channel right you
were talking about it as you started it
and how how did you find that experience
like that seems like that would be
different than the sort of courses and
stuff that you had been doing before
yeah I just I just thought it would be
interesting um there was no like
business reason for it I just thought it
would be interesting because I think
even if you're working at a full-time
job I think most people's dream is to
kind of run their own thing I I'm not
saying everybody wants to be like
entrepreneurial like that but like if
you could just wave a magic wand and
make your salary building your own app
like I feel like we would all kind of
maybe in this room but I feel like if I
surveyed like my kids Elementary School
class 90% of them would say they want to
be a YouTuber yeah so you know you're
living the dream you're right next to
astronaut and firefighter that's right
no but I meant like the developers right
the developers had a job like yeah I'm
sure you would love to be you know
making full so anyway I thought that
would be like interesting just to share
the process share what I was learning um
because the idea was to like shift my
whole Channel I I shift yours a lot by
the way then this way then this way um
so the idea was to shift my channel cuz
I was kind of getting bored with like
typical tutorials again I felt stagnant
like I said like I felt like a
mathematician teaching fifth grade math
and felt stagnant so I was like okay I'm
going to shift my content towards like
indev you know the business of apps cuz
that's truly like what I was genuinely
interested that's what I wanted to do
yeah and then I failed and then the
videos didn't get any views because like
you can talk about doing it but like
unless you kind of have the authority
and The credibility of backing it up
like I've done this look I've built an
app to x amount of money whatever it is
then that has more staying power so
you're saying the content itself didn't
perform well yes it didn't well it
didn't perform well and I didn't perform
well so just those two combined uh I
didn't meaning the app itself yeah yeah
yeah oh that's interesting okay so yeah
so the app itself uh you built it it's
like really good for your personal use
case uh it's a it's an iOS and iPad app
iOS iPad and Mac Mac so I mean I use it
every day I love it I mean I'm a little
biased but
I love it and it's like super Niche
because it's not just for people who
have a YouTube channel like that's
pretty niche as it is it's people who
have a YouTube channel that are making
like decent income off of it yeah right
so it's like pretty Niche and it's hard
I know Ariel's still here but it's hard
to Target for ASO cuz like YouTube's got
to be my title but then that gets a lot
of like YouTube people and then people
are looking for YouTube analytics like
people that are actually looking for a
YouTube business tracker that's tough I
need to talk to him you need to talk to
Ariel yeah he might have some tips for
you um oh that okay that's cool so
you you built this out you're proud of
it you go to launch it what was your
strategy for trying to make this like a
success from like a marketing standpoint
yeah so the the plan was to try to get
to some number 5K Mr 10K Mr something
like respectable and then go to partner
with one of the YouTube gurus so there's
there's a whole YouTube genre to teach
you how to YouTube um and they have a
giant following so the idea was like and
I wanted to get initial TR ction on my
own because I didn't want to give up a
lot of the company cuz I didn't want to
just pay them to sponsor I wanted them
to be a partner in it invest it all that
stuff so I was like if I go to them now
I have to give them so much cuz there's
there's nothing here you know but if I
can go and show hey this is making 10K a
month it's already got x amount of users
you can see the trajectory now if they
for one that'd be probably more
attractive to partner with for them and
then two I wouldn't have to like give up
the entire company you know as a
percentage okay so you're trying to make
this a successful enough thing first how
well that was the plan um um
how I just did like Google or not Google
adws but uh App Store ads and I guess I
never really got to the point where I I
was basically I don't have a good answer
I I didn't really have a plan that would
be challenging cuz you you have a really
big audience but that doesn't overlap a
lot with it's kind of like I Curtis is
here I think I may have literally
referenced this in the last time I did
this live episode but he talked about in
slopes how it's hard to find an audience
for something that's Niche that has
nothing to do with the like iOS
Community like we all know each other
and like 9 to5 and all these different
uh uh press Outlets like there's kind of
mechanisms for that but if 9o5 Mac wrote
an article about your app it's like how
many people are reading 9o5 Mac that are
also running YouTube businesses four of
them four there's exactly four yeah so
like yeah distribution feels incredibly
difficult it sounds like you had a plan
if you could get it high enough and the
the goal was to just go with like
adverti paid adver I actually just
remembered what derailed me took I
completely forgot about this so I had a
co-founder in the beginning and it was
good to have accountability to keep each
other you know like if I didn't feel
like working on the app one day he would
submit a poll request and I would feel
like like oh I didn't anything yeah
there it's like a gym buddy right you
have that accountability and he got
hired at Apple so obviously yeah
couldn't compete with that what a jerk
yeah yeah he's on the watch Team now um
so that really took the wind out of my
sales and that derailed me for a little
bit and then I kind of like never really
recovered from that because then I
switched back to like okay let me get
some money coming in uh so I just kind
of switch back to videos and courses
that's that's kind of what I do I bounce
back and forth between courses and
YouTube videos and then a a season of
working on the app yeah but I have to go
back because the app doesn't make any
money so it's like I'm putting all my
human capital all my effort into this
thing that makes no money when I have
this thing that is pretty leveraged
right with the YouTube channel it's like
oh I can do just a little bit work here
make a good amount of money or I can do
a lot of work here and make no money so
there's that like yeah that's
interesting it feels like it feels like
you're in a place right now where you're
a little frustrated are you proud of the
app itself like are you happy that you
did this well I'm happy I did it I'm not
I am proud but I'm not proud I think we
all feel this right because the app you
probably have in your head like I I
would say the app I've built so far is
like 10% of what in it was is my vision
so when I say I'm not proud of it it's
like and you know you know all the flaws
of your app so yeah I think Jordan
Morgan said something in a blog post
about that like you're you're too close
to it right you you know all the flaws
you know what could be better so when I
when you ask me if I'm proud of it I'm
like oh I can do so much more I want to
do so much more um but yeah at the end
of the day yeah I'm proud of it but does
it feel good to have something out I
mean I guess you already had something
out there with the YouTube channel
that's going so it's not I feel like for
a lot of Indies like me it was like that
was our first sort of taste of like
there's real people out there that I'm
like impacting you know but I guess you
get that a lot with the courses and with
like you talked about seeing people move
into the the community and do well and
everything yeah and coming like here
like I had so many people come up and
just say I just want to say thank you
just want to thank you you help you help
me out so much and I I've said the same
thing a bunch of times but it's like
it's so cool to put like faces to those
views right yeah all I is an avatar or
just like a view count and it's like you
you kind of like intellectually know
you're helping people but actually see
them shake their hand hear their story
like that's just a like I've been very
energized by this conference and like
talking to everybody oh yeah yeah this
place is incredible yeah good um so
something like you've done something new
just recently related to your career in
business you're actually like working
for somebody again which it sounds like
you haven't been doing for a while not
quite yet I start I start Friday oh you
start Friday okay what's the story there
yeah I had my course launch and then I
had this thing to do here that we're
talking about um this little thing um so
yeah so I start Friday um but it's uh I
wanted to work at a a startup a small
team um because you know just working by
myself out of my apartment on the
YouTube channel just got lonely after a
while I have no one to talk to there's
no team it's just okay so yeah I was
like and again that whole like I feel
like I wasn't pushing myself even like
my app is nothing crazy right and all
this AI stuff The Vision Pro I was like
man I want to be like working in the
future again or feel like I'm working in
the future kind of thing or like where
things are going so I put out a tweet um
saying basically hey I'm available for
hire you know let me know and I said I'm
looking for a cool team cool project I
don't know if I said this in the Tweet
but in my mind I was like yeah pay me
market rate but it's not like a money
thing right cuz also when you work for
yourself for 5 years working for
somebody else again is very hard yeah
yeah especially having the backup like
my my tolerance for BS probably be low
so I like I don't need this out so I
wanted to make sure cool team cool
project was like number one priority it
couldn't be just a pure money play um
yeah so I put out that tweet and luckily
the the CEO of this company called
podcast AI um building an extra ation
podcast app we can get into that in a
second but telling the story of how it
happened um luckily he'd kind of been a
fan of the channel been following me for
a while um he had another product in the
Creator space that I like consulted on
for a little bit so there's a little bit
of a prior relationship so I gave that
context to to say cuz I went from tweet
to offer in 8 hours well it's you're
like 10 years later you're finally
cashing in on what you originally
started the YouTube channel for Bring It
full circle creating a network yeah I
was like I was like one day someone's
going to hire me just because they know
me like that's what I said when I
started so yeah 7 years later uh it
actually happened yeah that's I mean
that's really cool I know like it's
everybody's experience is different and
right now I almost feel weird like being
really proud of working at Revenue cat
cuz I know it's like a hard environment
for everybody but it it really is like
if you invest in the community um it
might take a very long time but those
relationships especially if you're being
honest and being real and being helpful
to people that comes back to help you
yeah like I like to say I always
internally track like the Goodwill I
have with my audience it's like a weird
thing as like a Creator cuz when you
sell something when it's too high you're
like I'm just going to like be mean for
a little bit no no it's like when you if
I'm constantly which it probably feels
that way now cuz they just launched the
course if anyone that follows me on
Twitter when I'm constantly like here's
my next course here's this right that's
all I tweet about you're like draining
Goodwill when you do that all had
newsletters we read for a while that we
like really liked and then you're like
well but lately like everything they do
is about this product they have right
right yeah so I try to keep it internal
like level of that and I released a
bunch of my courses for free lately put
them on YouTube so I felt like I built
up enough Goodwill and launched the
course so now I'm now I'm probably
spamming the hell out of you guys
probably annoyed but yeah I'm in I'm in
that mode right now but that'll stop
soon um yeah that's funny I mean that's
that's how I talk to my kids I talk
about uh earning trust and spending
trust and it's like you can lose trust
as well obviously by doing something
wrong but you also spend it by like uh
asking for something or whatever and if
you do that too much and you're not
building it back up it drains out like
that's that's how relationships work
yeah so I I mean I always try to give
more than like I get that makesense yeah
yeah yeah yeah and like I mean having a
YouTube channel kind of dedicated to
helping right Junior developers get into
the field feels like uh it would be
fulfilling in that way yeah yeah that's
good cool well uh I'm going to try and
do Josh a favor here and try to start
wrapping up okay so I'm going to ask you
the question I ask everybody to end the
show I'm going to read it cuz if I don't
I'll say it wrong uh so what is a person
or people out there that have inspired
you that you'd recommend others check
out yeah so there's there's kind of two
paths I want to go with this I'm going
to say I don't know this person I just
we interact on Twitter a little bit and
I'm probably going to butcher the handle
because it's a Twitter handle it's
Aether uh aurelus or something like that
I can tweet it out but uh they're young
put it in the show notes yeah they're
they're a young kid they're
designer/developer and it's kind of part
of the build in public thing so the two
paths I want to go is with the youth so
I don't know how old he is he's in
college right so anytime I see like
teenagers or super young people like
putting in work putting out good apps it
just blows my mind like I said I didn't
start coding till 32 at 18 all I cared
about was dominating in Golden Eye like
I did not care about like building a
career was like yeah okay you know so it
just blows my mind so I get super
inspired when I see the youths of the
world you know I feel like I just H 10
years like man kids these days yeah but
no it blows my mind I'm like oh my God
what I was doing at 181 19 like yeah
like the Swift student challenge that
Apple does for dubdub every year is the
same kind of deal where uh you go and
look at their projects and it well
looking at their projects is always like
really cool but if you've ever been in
person and or like talked to those kids
man yeah I do feel old uh it's always
like they start talking about things
that like I I still don't even
understand you forget that they're in
like high school or college and then
they start talking about like finals and
you're like wait what hold on this isn't
right yeah yeah they're yeah we're all
do
I didn't know that about him that he was
still in college at the time cuz I
emailed him I was like hey can I hire
you to like take a pass at my app
creator viiew like don't don't Cod it or
anything just like take a you cuz he was
doing all kinds of cool little
interactions like nothing over the top
just like the perfect amount of subtle
interaction like Apple touch right like
that we're all like obsessed with and
he's really good at it and he was like I
can't for another 6 months cuz I have
like finals or something like that I was
like wait a second I was like oh man um
so yeah so they used and then the whole
buildin public thing um not the Mr
updaters of the world but the uh like
the people that are actually here's this
cool feature I build or here's my new
onboard flow or here's the setting
screen what do you think kind of thing
like I I love seeing what everyone's
like building out there and it just
makes me want to you know add that to my
app or build some version of it my app
yeah yeah it's really fun seeing
somebody uh who like I'm not like
usually one who will click on the
hashtags and read through everything but
that is one where when I see one that's
interesting I'll actually like click it
and you're right like a lot of times
it's a bunch of grifters but but then
you get those ones where like you can
see a nugget of something exciting but
it's really early and then like you
follow that person and then you know a
year later they're like really
successful or they've made this really
cool thing and you feel like you got to
like kind of be a part of
it feel like you discovered a band
before they got cool yeah yeah yeah yeah
that's exactly what it is oh I knew them
whenever they were nothing uh yeah it's
yeah it's that is really exciting that's
one of the great things about I mean the
internet I guess but just being to find
people early on in those uh in those
paths and then watch them grow so that'
be my pleas share what you're building
on Twitter or Macedon whatever you're on
like I love seeing it I know everyone
else loves seeing it too yeah no that's
great uh yeah that'll be in the show
notes I'll uh I'm probably already
follow this person I'll see their I'll
see their profile picture and
immediately know but I never know
anybody's actual handle exactly yeah all
right well I'm going to try to actually
wrap this up then so where can people
find you and your work yeah so uh just
youtube.com/ Sean Allen and then on
Twitter Macedon is Sean Allen Dev all
right sweet all right that's the end
normally there's music but clapping will
suffice
perfect thanks for listening if you'd
like to discuss the show you can find me
on Twitter Macedon threads or whatever
the social media app of the day is at
Charlie M chapman. me we'd really
appreciate a rating or review on your
podcast app of choice and you can find
show notes and more at launched fm.com
[Music]